# ALPHONES KIPROTICH BETT

Phone number: +254728418311 Email: alphoneskips2017@gmail.com

A Computer Scientist with experience in Networking, Front-end Web Development, Programming Languages (C#, Python) and Adobe Photoshop (Social Media Graphics, Flyers Photo Editing, Logo Design, Posters). I'm an industrious person who believes in hard work, commitment, determination and upholds integrity as core values in life.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

**COMPANY:** KENYA REVENUE AUTHORITY(KRA)

**JOB TITLE: INTERN** 

FROM: JAN 2023 - PRESENT

RESPONSIBILITIES

1.ICT

- Provide technical assistance to staff and customers on hardware and software-related issues.
- Install, configure, and troubleshoot computer systems, hardware, and software.
- Monitor system performance and troubleshoot any issues.
- User and system support.

#### 2.MARKETING & COMMUNICATION

- KRA PIN registration and retrieval.
- Taxpayer training and education.
- Individual and non-individual returns filing for various tax-obligations.

**COMPANY:** MINISTRY OF TRANSPORT, INFRASTRUCTURE, HOUSING, URBAN DEVELOPMENT AND PUBLIC WORKS.

**JOB TITLE:** ICT INDUSTRIAL ATTACHEMENT

**FROM:** MAY 2022 – AUGUST 2022

RESPONSIBILITIES

- Installation and configuration of networking equipment.
- Networking-Termination of Ethernet Cables, Configuration of Networks and connection.
- Data protection, updating virus protection software and creating firewalls
- Troubleshooting and resolving networking issues in departments within the State Departments.
- User and system support.
- Monitoring and fault management.
- Operating Systems installation and Partitioning and formatting of hard disks.
- Removing dust in CPUs in different Departments using Air Blower machine.

#### **EDUCATION**

AUGUST,2018-OCTOBER, 2022

**SOUTH EASTERN KENYA UNIVERSITY: BSc. COMPUTER SCIENCE** 

JANUARY, 2014 - DECEMBER, 2017

KABIANGA HIGH SCHOOL: KENYA CERTIFICATE OF SECONDARY EDUCATION(KCSE)

JANUARY, 2005 - DECEMBER, 2013

KAPKWEN PRIMARY SCHOOL: KENYA CERTIFICATE OF PRIMARY EDUCATION EDUCATION(KCPE)

### **CERTIFICATIONS**

AUG, 2023 - OCT, 2023

**CYBERSECURITY ESSENTIALS:** AFRICAN ADVANCED LEVEL TELECOMMUNICATIONS INSTITUTE Cyber security being a world of experts and criminals, the cyber security cube, Threats, Security and attacks, art of protecting secrets, art of ensuring integrity, protecting cyber security domain.

AUG. 2023 - OCT. 2023

**NETWORK SECURITY:** AFRICAN ADVANCED LEVEL TELECOMMUNICATIONS INSTITUTE Securing networks, monitoring and managing devices, ACLs and firewalls, Intrusion prevention, layer 2 and endpoint security, cryptography, VPNs and ASA

AUG, 2023 - OCT, 2023

PCAP: AFRICAN ADVANCED LEVEL TELECOMMUNICATIONS INSTITUTE

Introduction to python and computer programming, data types, Boolean values, function tuples, dictionaries, data processing and basic operators. Programming essentials in python.

MAY, 2023 - JUL, 2023

**CYBERSECURITY ESSENTIALS: KENYATTA UNIVERSITY** 

Global implications of cyber threats, ways in which networks are vulnerable to attack, impact of cyberattacks and approach to threat detection and defense.

### **SKILLS**

- Networking-Termination of Ethernet Cables, Configuration of Networks and connection.
- Operating Systems installation and Partitioning and formatting of hard disks.
- HTML, CSS, JS, C# (.NET CORE Frameworks)
- System administration & management.

- Database development, maintenance and administration using SQL (Microsoft SQL Server & MySQL).
- Adobe Photoshop(Photo editing, Logo Design, Banners, Flyers, Poster)

### **INERESTS**

- Learning new Technologies through documentation and the internet.
- Interested in doing volunteers or community work during my free time.
- Participating in social activities i.e. playing volleyball, listening music and watching movies and international football games.

## **REFEREES**

 DR. CASPER SHIKALI Lecturer(ICT)- South Eastern Kenya University TEL:0720832863

Email: cshikali@seku.ac.ke

2. MR. CHARLES KIPRONO TURGUT TSO HEAD- KRA NAIVASHA TSO Email: charles.turgut@kra.go.ke TEL:0723926789

3. Mr. Cornelius Tonui CEO-Micropoint Systems, Nairobi Email:ctonui@gmail.com

TEL:0720472020